Heart
Stirring
Pangs
Did you mean: Love?
（日代(ひしろ)）“もしかして 恋”
"Did you mean... love"?
まさか ありえない
No...
Impossible.
それは ありえない
That's just...
...not possible.
〜♪
This Isn't the First Time
（海崎(かいざき)）あー
Hey there! Arata?
（大神(おおが)）あ もしもし 新太(あらた)？
How's your Golden Week going?
ゴールデンウィーク
いかがお過ごし？
What do you want, Oga?
（海崎）何だよ 大神
いかがも何も 家にいるけど
It's going nowhere.
I'm just lying around at home.
Oh, really?
（大神）あ ほんと？
今ねえ 実は
杏(あん)ちゃんと一緒にねえ
Right now, I'm actually with An-chan...
...right outside your place!
（大神）新太の
部屋の前にいるんだ
Open up!
（小野屋(おのや)･大神）
あーけーてー！
Huh? Hang on...
え！ ちょっと待って
What are you doing here?!
何の用だよ いきなり
（大神）この前 言ったじゃん
I told you the other day
that we'd need to study
over Golden Week!
ゴールデンウィークは勉強会だって
Hello?
もしもーし
Gimme ten minutes!
（海崎）10分待って！
Think he's got something
he doesn't want us to see?
何か見られちゃまずいものでも
あるのかな？
Probably.
Damn it! If you're
coming over, tell me first!
（海崎）くそっ 来るなら来るって
前もって言えよ！
How do they even know where I live?!
っていうか 何でうち知ってんだよ
におい
It reeks!
Come in.
どうぞ
That took forever!
（小野屋）もう 待ったよー
Thanks for having us!
（大神）お邪魔しまーす
Sit wherever.
（海崎）適当に座ってて
お茶ぐらいしかねえけど いい？
I've only got tea. Want some?
Oh, I'll help!
（小野屋）ああ あたし手伝うよ
あっ いい！ いいから座ってて
It's okay!
I've got it! You sit down!
（小野屋）そう？
（海崎）うん うん
You sure?
（海崎）はあ…
（大神）新太 これ何？
Arata, what is this?
え！ 何が？
What?
This.
An MD.
（海崎）ＭＤじゃん
（小野屋）ＭＤ？
MD?
（大神）ああ フロッピーか
Oh, a floppy?
No, an MD.
（海崎）ＭＤです
音楽が入ってんだよ
It's got music on it.
へえー
Seriously?
（海崎）マジかよ
今どきの子 ＭＤ通じねえんだ
Kids these days haven't even heard of them?
You've got some neat stuff!
物持ちいいんだね
Okay! Let's start studying!
（大神）それでは—
再試 合格目指して
勉強会を始めます
Let's pass those make-ups!
おーう！
おーう
あー 疲れたー
I'm beat...
You need to focus!
（大神）集中力なさすぎ
（海崎）ちゃんと解いたろ
I solved it!
Only one!
まだ１問じゃん
Actually, Arata,
I dunno how you got into Aoba.
つか新太
ほんと よく青葉(あおば)入れたよね
We're a pretty decent prep school.
（大神）
うち そこそこ進学校だよ？
How did you get in when you're so dumb?
この学力で入れるとは
Th-That's so rude!
しっ 失礼な
You can't call it rude at this point.
It's just a fact.
いや 失礼とか もう
そういうレベルの話じゃなくて—
マジで
（海崎）うっ
まあ それを言ったら
あたしもだし
I guess that goes for me, too?
Maybe this year's transfer exam was easy?
今年の編入試験は
簡単だったのかもね
（大神）えー そうだったのかなあ
Huh? Was it really?
An, you're, like, always on your phone.
杏って何か
いっつも携帯いじってるよな
Huh? Am I?
えっ そう？
Yeah, I thought the same thing.
あー それ 俺も思ってた
お昼とかよくさあ
At lunch or whenever.
Is that so? Sorry!
そうだっけ？ ごめん
Who are you chatting with?
誰とそんなやり取りしてんの？
Boyfriend?
（海崎）彼氏とか？
（小野屋）やーだ 新太君 セクハラ
Come on, Arata-kun!
Sexual harassment!
ごっ ごめん そんなつもりは…
Sorry, I didn't mean to...
（小野屋）冗談 冗談
I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
ごめんね 無意識だった
気をつけるね
Sorry, I didn't realize.
I'll be more careful.
By the way, Oga-kun...
（小野屋）そういえば 大神君
（大神）ん？
You wear clothes like those normally.
（小野屋）私服は普通に着るんだね
（大神）普通？
Normally?
I mean,
ほら 制服のカーデは
すっごいゆるっと着てんじゃん？
the uniform's cardigan
is super baggy on you.
Oh, that's a hand-me-down
from my brother.
あー あれは兄ちゃんの
お下がりなんだよね
（海崎）つか大神 体 薄いよな
Plus you're really skinny.
No wonder you could only throw
that handball two meters.
そりゃハンドボールも
２メートルしか飛ばねえわ
（大神）１メートルに
言われたくないわ！
You're one to talk, Mr. One Meter!
ふふふ ま それでも
大神君はモテモテだろうけどね
Well, it probably hasn't stopped you
from being popular.
だな 男の俺から見ても
イケメンだなって思うし
For sure.
Even I find you good looking,
and I'm a dude.
（大神）ん？
（小野屋）てか—
If only he'd just go out with her already.
さっさと
つきあっちゃえばいいのにね
（海崎）まったくですな
このクソ鈍感男
Seriously. He's just so dense!
What are we talking about?
何の話？ これ
Oga-kun, if you got a girlfriend,
大神君が彼女 作ってくれたら—
あたし 再試
合格できそうな気がする
I think I could pass these make-ups.
Me, too.
俺も
（大神）だから何の話だよ？
Seriously, what are we talking about?!
You always derail things like this!
大体そうやって
いつも脱線するだろ？
ほんと頼むから
ちゃんと勉強して！
Please! Just study properly!
（海崎･小野屋）はーい
Okay.
All said and done,
（海崎）何だかんだ
ちょっと楽しいな こういうの
this sort of thing is kinda fun.
Though calling them "friends"
（海崎）友達だなんて—
might be too impudent of me,
a guy who's ten years older.
10も年上の俺が
厚かましいかもしれないけどな
Okay, this could actually work out!
何とかなりそうな感じに
なってきたなあ
Numbers... Numbers scary...
（海崎）数字… 数字 怖い…
I feel sick...
（小野屋）気持ち悪い…
Oga...
大神 普段こんなに
ぶっ通しで勉強してんの？
You study this hard all the time?
（大神）はあ？
何言ってんの これぐらいで
What? This is nothing!
Our standards are totally different...
あたしたちとは基準が違うね
I mean, you'll be in trouble if you
don't pass the make-ups next week.
だって来週には再試
合格しとかないとやばいと思うしさ
再来週はもう 中間テストだよ
Midterms are the week after.
And if we fail those?
（海崎）それでまた赤点あったら？
（大神）また再試
More make-ups.
（海崎）マジかよ
再試無限ループじゃねえか
Are you serious?
It's an infinite loop of make-ups!
You don't plan to get out?
回避しようって気はないの？
Anyway, I think you'd better pass next week.
（大神）とにかく 来週もう
合格しとくのがいいと思うよ
What about your own studies?
（海崎）そういう大神こそ勉強は？
Are you sure you should be
hanging around with us?
いいのか？
こんな俺らにつきあってて
Final Interview
3rd and 1st
Resume Deadline
（大神）ここまで再試が
長引くなんて 予想外だったんだよ
I didn't expect you to
fail this many make-ups.
So he says,
だってよ…
An?!
（大神）
ど… どうしたの 新太 急に
Where'd that come from?
あっ あ いや これは その…
Er... I, uh...
There!
そい！
There was a bug on the wall!
（海崎）何か壁に 何か 虫がいた
（小野屋）ひえーっ うそー！
No way!
B-But I got it!
（海崎）し… しとめたから
（携帯電話の着信音）
（大神）あ ごめん
Sorry.
I'll just pop outside.
（大神）ちょっと 外出るね
（海崎）ぬ！
N-N-N-No!
だだ… だっ… だめだ！
な… 何で？
Why?
My laundry's drying!
洗濯物とか干してるし
いいじゃん 気にしないよ
Big deal. I don't mind.
（海崎）俺が気にする！
（大神）え…
I do!
They're gonna hang up! Answer it!
（海崎）
早く出ねえと切れるぞ！ 出ろ！
All right...
分かったよ
もしもし？ 大神です
お疲れさまです
Hello?
This is Oga.
Oh, thanks for all the hard work.
Yeah?
はい あー はい
Yeah.
Right.
（大神）分かりました
今から行きます はい
Got it. I'll be right over.
Okay.
Sorry. I've gotta go to work.
ごめん 俺 バイトに
行かなきゃならなくなった
（海崎）バイトって？
（大神）３丁目のコンビニ
Work?
The convenience store on Third.
人手が足りないみたいで
急に来てくれって
They're short-staffed and
asked me to come in.
Oh, is that why you always
rush out when school ends?
（小野屋）あー いつも学校
終わったら すぐ帰るの それ？
うん ごめん
Yup. Sorry.
So, you two make sure
you get through the rest.
ってわけで ２人は残りも
ちゃんと頑張るように
はーい お疲れ
We will! Thanks!
（海崎）
ちょ！ ちょっと待て 大神
Whoa there, Oga!
Take An with you!
（海崎）杏も連れて帰れよ
（大神）何で？
Why?
This isn't good!
まずいだろ 一人暮らしの男の家に
I'm a dude living alone here!
Huh?
え？ 何で？
So what?
Do you actually have the brain
of a high school boy?!
お前の頭は本当に男子高校生か？
何だよ その驚きの白さ！
How can you be so astonishingly pure?!
No can do. You've gotta
finish your quota.
だーめ
まだノルマ残ってるでしょ？
Bye!
（大神）じゃあね
（海崎）あ…
あ… 杏は
まだ帰らなくて大丈夫なの？
A-Are you sure you don't want to leave?
Yeah, I'm good.
うん 大丈夫
Oga-kun's so nice, isn't he?
優しいよね 大神君
He's got his own studies and job,
自分の勉強や
バイトもあるだろうに—
but he teaches us with all his heart.
あたしたちに
一生懸命 教えてくれて
We have to pass!
絶対 合格しようね
Yeah.
Hello.
（夜明(よあけ)）お疲れさまです
サポート課の夜明です
This is Yoake from Support.
Requesting permission for status
surveillance on subject no. 002.
被験者ナンバー002の
状態観察の許可をお願いします
Status surveillance?
（リライフ社員）状態観察ですね
少々お待ちください
Please hold.
Connected.
（機械アナウンス）接続しました
（小野屋）ねえ 新太君
Hey, Arata-kun.
What was up with that calendar?
さっきのカレンダーって
何だったの？
Notes about interviews and resumes...
（小野屋）面接とか 履歴書とか
What were those?
あれ 何？
Work...
（海崎）バイト—
I guess?
のこと かな？
I was looking for part-time work.
バイト探してたから 俺
（小野屋）ふーん
Arata-kun, did you ever work...
（小野屋）
新太君 もしかして前—
...at a convenience store?
コンビニでバイトしてた？ 駅前の
By the station?
Y-Yeah.
あ ああ よく分かったね
How'd you know?
やっぱり！
I knew it!
I actually met you there!
あたし コンビニで新太君に
会ってるんだよ
見覚え ない？
Remember me now?
Sorry.
（海崎）ごめん
（小野屋）だよねえ
Figures.
You seemed more grown-up there.
コンビニの新太君
もっと大人っぽくって—
And really cool.
それもかっこよかったの
Well... I guess...
いやあ それは…
コンビニの制服って
年上に見えるから
...the store uniforms make you look older?
（小野屋）えー そうなの？
Do they really?
But I'm really glad that we're
the same age, in the same school,
でも 同い年で 同じ学校で—
and that we met again
in the same class.
同じクラスで再会できて
すごくうれしい
（小野屋）運命みたい
It's like destiny.
That voice is...!
（夜明）この声は…
The regulation five-minute status
surveillance has concluded.
（機械アナウンス）規定による
５分間の状態観察を終了しました
This is Yoake from Support.
（夜明）サポート課 夜明です
被験者ナンバー002—
Detecting unusual circumstances with
subject no. 002, Kaizaki Arata.
海崎新太に異常事態を感知
状態観察の延長をお願いします
Requesting surveillance extension.
Permission granted. Connect now?
（リライフ社員）許可が下りました
すぐに接続しますか？
Please do.
お願いします
I...
（小野屋）あたし—
...fell in love with you at first sight.
新太君に一目ぼれだったの
So being alone with you
like this is exciting.
だから 今 こうして２人きりで
ドキドキしてる
（海崎）あ…
（小野屋）新太君は—
Arata-kun, does being alone
with me do nothing for you?
あたしと２人きりで何ともない？
Aren't you...
ドキドキ しない？
...excited?
えっ あ いや…
Uh, well...
ちょっと ごめん
急すぎて 頭が回らなくて
I... sorry.
This is too sudden. I can't think.
ふふ 顔 赤くなってる
You're turning red.
そ そりゃあ…
W-Well, duh.
Are you in love with anyone?
（小野屋）今 好きな子はいる？
（海崎）え？
（海崎）何で日代(ひしろ)さんなんだよ！
Why Hishiro-san?!
I don't think so...
いない と思う
You don't think so, huh?
“思う”なんだ ふふっ
Then...
じゃあ—
If I said I wanted to be your girlfriend,
あたしが“新太君の彼女に
なりたいです”って言ったら—
あり？
would you accept?
Arata-kun...
新太君
好きなの
I love you.
If it's consensual,
it's not illegal or anything.
（夜明）合意であれば
違法でもなんでもない
But Kaizaki-san could never
do anything like that!
だが それ以前に—
海崎さんは そんなことは
できない人だと何度も…
How many times...!
（小野屋）新太君…
（海崎）ちょっと 杏…
Arata-kun...
Hey, An!
I can't, An.
（海崎）だめだよ 杏
You should take better care of yourself.
もっと自分を大事にしなきゃ
This sort of thing isn't...
こんなことしてちゃ だ…
Yoake?
（海崎）よ… あけ…
つーか ドア！ 鍵！ あれ？
Wait, the door!
The lock! Huh?!
Oh, don't worry, I didn't break it.
ああ 壊したとかじゃないですよ
ちゃんと合鍵です
I have a spare key.
（海崎）なんで持ってる！
（小野屋）え え？
Why do you have one?!
Huh?
クラスの夜明君 だよね？
合鍵とか…
Yoake-kun from class, right?
A spare key?
（小野屋）そんな仲だったの？
（海崎）違ーう！
Are you two lovers?!
No!
もう これ以上は
見過ごせないよ
That's enough, Onoya.
（夜明）小野屋
（海崎）えっ？
Starting with no honorific?
（小野屋）いきなり呼び捨て？
And your hand...
しかも この手
Would you let go?
離してくれないかなあ？
何？
What?
Are you mad because you thought
I'd take Arata-kun from you?
もしかして新太君を
取られそうになって—
それで怒ってるの？
（海崎）え ちょ…
Wait...
We're not allowed to make
excessive contact with our subjects.
（夜明）
被験者への過度な干渉はＮＧ
How many times do I have to tell you?
（夜明）何度言っても聞かない
Eating lunch with him every day...
毎日一緒に昼を食べ
わざと再試につきあい—
Deliberately joining his studies...
あげく うちにまで押しかけて
何してるんだ
And now forcing your way into his home...
What are you doing?
This isn't a laughing matter, Onoya.
悪ふざけが過ぎるぞ 小野屋
（海崎）よ 夜明さん
Y-Yoake-san, what...?
（海崎）何 言って…
（小野屋）あーあ
Aw!
何でバラしちゃうんですか
夜明先輩
Why'd you have to tell him, Yoake-senpai?
I could have done far more to support him
あたしのこと 本物の女子高生だと
思わせておいたほうが—
if he'd thought I was a real high school girl.
うまいことサポート
できたんじゃないですか？
（夜明）うるさい
Shut up!
この先 何をしでかすか
分かったもんじゃない
Who knows what else you'd do?
別に本気じゃないですよ
ちょっと試してみただけで
I wasn't, like, serious about him.
I was just testing him.
Um...
（海崎）あの…
（夜明･小野屋）ん？
Look...
もう いろいろと急展開すぎて—
There have been way too many twists,
and I'm not following this at all.
状況がいまいち
のみ込めないんですけど
I mean, I can sorta guess
from your conversation...
いや 会話的に
何となく予想はついたけど…
Do you work for the ReLIFE Laboratory?
リライフ研究所の人 ですか？
Hello! I'm Onoya An from the ReLIFE
Laboratory Support Division.
（小野屋）どうも リライフ研究所
サポート課の小野屋 杏といいます
Nice to meet you formally,
改めて よろしくお願いします
海崎新太さん
Kaizaki Arata-san!
Then what was...?
じゃ さっきの
一目ぼれとかって…
"Love at first sight"?
Oh...
Just kidding!
うっそー です！
Just... kidding!
Just
kidding!
（海崎）ああ… もしかして普段
携帯やたらいじってたのも…
So the reason you're always
on your phone...
ああ そうです そうです
Yeah, work conversations!
夜明先輩に“海崎さんに
近づきすぎ”って怒られたり—
Mostly Yoake-senpai yelling at me
for getting too close to you.
仕事関係です
So,
how old are you really?
本当は何歳なんだ？
Forever seventeen, dude!
永遠の17歳 だぞ？
Twenty-seven this year.
（小野屋）今年で27ですよ
（海崎）ん？
え！ じゃあ 夜明さんは？
Then what about Yoake-san?
（夜明）
あれ？ 言ってませんでしたっけ
Wait, did I not say?
Same age as you.
海崎さんと同じですよ
今年で28になります
Twenty-eight this year.
We're equals?!
タメだったのか
（小野屋）まあ だます形になって
悪かったですけど—
Well, sorry for tricking you,
but it was good practice
for the future, right?
今後のためのいい練習に
なったんじゃないですか？
（海崎）今後？
Future?
If a real high school girl comes after you,
you'll know just what to do!
（小野屋）今後
本物のＪＫに迫られても—
うまく対応できそうですよね
You were a total gentleman!
（小野屋）とっても紳士的でした
（海崎）うっ
あああ… もうやだ 疲れる…
Enough. This is wearing me out.
Is everyone in the Support Division
a walking joke?
サポート課ってのは
ふざけたやつしかいねえのか
（小野屋･夜明）失礼しちゃうなあ
How rude!
（夜明）似てるんだよ お前ら！
You're the same!
Grinning while you toy with people's hearts!
ニコニコと人の心を
もてあそびやがって！
（小野屋）別に ふざけてないですよ
I'm not joking around.
Today was a proper part
of your ReLIFE experience!
今日のだって
真面目なリライフ活動の一環です
どこが
How so?
Um... well...
うーんとですね
Sometimes subjects use the fact
that no one will remember them
たまに 自分に関する記憶が
消されるのをいいことに—
to do bad things.
悪用しちゃおうって
被験者がいるんですよね
Bad things?
（海崎）悪用って…
（小野屋）例えば—
Like messing around with high school girls.
それこそ女子高生と
遊んでやろうとか
I-I...
お 俺は…
Today, I believed in you,
but I tested your character a bit.
今日は 信用しつつも
海崎さんの人間性を—
ちょっとだけ試させてもらった
ってわけです
すみませんでした
Sorry about that!
ほんっと この困った後輩が
何を考えてるんだか分からなくて
Honestly, I have no idea what
goes through her head sometimes.
ねえ 小野屋
Right, Onoya?
うわー 夜明先輩 怒ってる
Yikes, Yoake-senpai's mad.
Seriously, I rushed here worried that
we'd have to cancel the experiment.
もう最悪 実験中止も
なくはないと慌てて来ちゃいました
いらない心配だったでしょ？
You needn't have.
That's the subject I picked for you!
さすが！
あたしが選んだ被験者です
（海崎）え？
（夜明）小野屋！
Onoya!
Not all of my confession was a lie.
さっきの告白 あながち
全部がうそではないんです
Wait, what?
（小野屋）
被験者候補の資料を見て—
When I looked over the subject data,
海崎さんという人間に
一目ぼれしたのは事実ですし—
I did fall for "Kaizaki Arata" at first sight.
And we did meet last year at your store.
去年 コンビニで
会ってるのも事実です
小野屋
Onoya!
Truth is, Yoake-senpai wasn't supposed
to be your support. I was.
（小野屋）
本当は海崎さんの担当—
夜明先輩じゃなくて
あたしがするはずだったんですよ
（夜明）小野屋！
（小野屋）なのにあたしったら—
Onoya!
But I couldn't finish
my training in a year!
１年で研修クリアできなくって
Training?
（海崎）研修？
He really doesn't want me to tell you,
さっきから バラされたく
ないみたいですけど—
but Yoake-senpai is the same.
夜明先輩もなんですよ
He was in training at Aoba for two years!
青葉で２年も研修して
The training period is only
supposed to last a year.
本当は研修期間は
１年なんですけどね
Right, Yoake-senpai?
ね 夜明先輩
That's right.
そうなんです
So in place of Onoya,
I took over as your support.
なので 僕が小野屋の代わりに
海崎さんの担当を引き受けて…
You may still be in training,
but you got too close!
研修とはいえ 近すぎるけどね
たいがいにして ほんと
Give it a rest, really.
てててて…
すみません すみません
Ow, ow, ow! Sorry, sorry!
Anyway, sorry for lots of things about today.
（小野屋）そういうわけで
今日はいろいろ すみませんでした
We hope to keep working with you.
（夜明）今後とも
よろしくお願いします
あ… お おう
S-Sure.
Stop that! Raise your heads!
ああ ってか やめろよ
顔上げろよ
I'm not that mad.
そんな 怒っちゃいねえよ
（海崎）夜明さんも
（小野屋）ふふっ
Yoake-san, c'mon!
（海崎）杏も
An, c'mon!
Sorry, Kaizaki-san.
（夜明）すみません 海崎さん
Half of that was true.
半分本当で 半分うそをつきました
Half of that wasn't.
〜♪
NEXT EPISODE
Senpai, what did you mean,
half of that was true and half wasn't?
（小野屋）先輩
“半分本当で半分うそ”
って何ですか？
（夜明）
言ってないだろ そんなこと
I never said anything like that.
（小野屋）聞こえた気が
したんですよね 心の声が
But I felt like I heard you thinking it.
（夜明）分かった風な
口きくねえ 小野屋
My, you talk like you know it all, Onoya.
Test Subject 001 -> 002
Well, I have known you for a long time.
（小野屋）つきあい 長いですから